

Lyla McBeath Fujiwara

www.jarofeyes.com 🌐

jarofeyesgames@gmail.com 🔀



Boston, MA

About Me

I'm a technically savvy, adaptable leader with a decade-long career in instructional design and technology. I've worked everywhere from rural Rwanda to Silicon Valley, leading teams to design and run an all-girls computer camp, produce online courses for over half a million students, and deliver Google News app features. I seek to apply my project management skills and educational design expertise to tabletop roleplaying games.

Tools

- Project Management Tools (Notion, Asana, Jira)
- Coding and Scripting (Kotlin, Java, Python, HTML, CSS)
- Google Workspace Suite
- Microsoft Office Suite
- Affinity Suite

Skills

- · Managing Timelines and Expectations
- Establishing Processes for Collaboration
- Meeting and Training Facilitation
- Curriculum Development and Instructional Design
- Leveraging Technology and Coding
- · Onboarding and Documentation
- · Mentoring New Talent

Work Experience

Freelancing as Jar of Eyes Games

2022 - Present

Game Designer and Project Lead

- Course Designer: Project Management for TTRPGs substack series, expanding into Project Leadership course for the Storytelling Collective.
- Project Lead: 10-person team for Encounters in the Radiant Citadel.
- Industry Recognition: 2023 Storytelling Collective Creative Laureate, 2023 Big Bad Con POC Scholar, D&D Beyond Community Spotlight for Out of Luck, Leading TRPGs Projects Panel Moderator.
- Selected TTRPG Work: Jukebox: The Karaoke Musical TTRPG (Creator, Kickstarter), Out of Luck (Creator, DMsGuild), Trouble Brewing in Port Nyanzaru (Writer, GameHole Con Adventures League), Adventure Patreon Pack (Writer, Bob World Builder).

2020 - 2022 Google

Android Engineer, Google News

- Tech Lead: First major Google News stories redesign launch. Ran A/B tests, presented to leadership, and facilitated decision-making between 15+ stakeholders.
- Android Developer: Google News features for COVID response and 2020 Elections. Awarded spot bonus for work.
- Team Leadership: Co-led test case FIXIT, co-led Android team documentation re-vamp, founded cross-team engineering study group, managed 2 software interns.

2017 - 2020 Google

Senior Android Developer Advocate

- Tech Lead: Developing Android Apps in Kotlin Course, the basis for Google's Android training. Wrote 3 lessons (93% positive rating), oversaw all technical content by 6 instructors, 40k+ students.
- Team Leadership: Founded the Speaker Mentorship program for Google I/O and ADS, founded codelab FIXITs, led team video strategy.
- **DevRel Leadership:** Founded DevRel Women's Lunch, co-organized 4 DEI events, conducted interviews, new hire mentor, 8 spot, and 28 peer bonuses.

2014 - 2017 Udacity

Android Content Developer and Instructor

- Course Creator: Online courses reaching over 500k students. Designed 7 intensive coding projects, filmed on-camera instruction, and wrote tutorials and interactive quizzes.
- Team lead: Onboarding process and training materials for new content development hires.

Education